### Contact

vipul.chauhan705@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/vipul-kumarchauhan (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)

С

C++

### Languages

Hindi (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

### Certifications

The Complete Product Management Course

Python Data Structures

Agile with Atlassian Jira

Python Programming

### **Publications**

Twitter Sentiment Analysis using Vader

# Vipul Kumar Chauhan

Product Manager | UX Enthusiast | Marketing Strategist Mumbai

### Summary

Passionate Product Manager with 3 years of experience in conceptualizing & shipping 12+ products in Health & Fitness, Social Networking, and E-learning domain. Additional expertise in Product Marketing, UI/UX Design, Consumer Science, and Strategic Growth.

# Experience

### Fitternity

Associate Product Manager
July 2019 - Present (1 year 2 months)

Mumbai Area, India

- Managed concept-to-launch of 10+ digital products including the core product
- OnePass. Defined user flow, action funnels ,and conversion funnels for various consumers types.
- Tracked stage-wise product growth and drew inferences to progressively improve & integrate product features.
- Analyzed data from Google Analytics, Appsflyer, Firebase & CleverTap to derive insights and to define product USP KPI's.
- Conceptualized designs and UX flow for multiples products by leveraging data points like exit pages, page click patterns, scroll depth ,and more.
- Analyzed market depth, market trends, competitor offerings, consumer feedback to create and strategize effective marketing campaigns.
- Defined detailed requirements : PRD's, user stories ,and scenarios to articulate the product and its offerings across multiple stakeholders.
- Utilized tactical strategies to prioritize development to achieve product growth and revenue targets.
- Experience Managing intricate B2B projects from clients like Reliance, Aditya Birla Wellness , SBI and more.

DigiKaushal Strategy Consultant January 2019 - June 2019 (6 months)

- Strategised 20L revenue growth plan for Digikausal at major education hubs and centers across India.
- Performed extensive market research ,consumer need evaluation and product-market fit analysis.
- Strategised product pricing for a marker entry value at a 50% profit cap

#### Ceekr

**Product Analyst** 

January 2018 - June 2019 (1 year 6 months)

New Delhi, Delhi, India

- Actively participated in Product Feature Ideation. Prepared Product mock-ups for the same.
- Performed extensive Market Research and Market Need Analysis, to develop Product Placement and GTM strategies.
- Actively worked with the Design and Content team towards refining the Platform UI/UX.
- Responsible for execution of B2B and B2C outbound Marketing Strategies, Customer Persona modelling and Customer Acquisition Strategies (B2C and B2B).
- Managed the weekly Scrum and also the Jira ticket system.

### Internshala

Student Partner

October 2017 - February 2018 (5 months)

New Delhi Area, India

Worked with Internshala as Internshala Student Partner(Virtual Internship). Advertised Internshala and related events at college and among my communicational network. Advertised using the word -to- mouth marketing and social media marketing.

### YourShell

**Business Intelligence Analyst** 

September 2017 - January 2018 (5 months)

New Delhi Area, India

Worked as a Business Intelligence Analyst at YourShell. Helped gather data on the hostel and temporary housing options near Delhi University region using various technical and non-technical resources. Also participated in various other roles in the company, including Operations and HR. Also helped in countering other market leader using data gathering and research analysis.

QOS Technology Data Analyst June 2017 - July 2017 (2 months) Bangalore

Worked as a Data Analyst on Sentiment Analysis based Project. The project was a three stage project as described below:

The Company uses Happyfox ticketing services for client query handling.
 the first stage was to Configure Apache Kafka to get tickets from Happyfox API and

filter unnecessary data out and pass only the required data sets.

2. Having Kafka stream the required data the next stage was to connect Spark to Kafka so that they could communicate and the required data could be received by

Spark. Following this, required developing a machine learning model using Spark's MLlib library and perform sentiment analysis over the ticket message content.

3. The final stage of the project was to deploy the Sentiment result over to a web portal.

Air India Limited Student Intern January 2017 - March 2017 (3 months) New Delhi

Worked as an Intern in the Air India Computer Center. As the part of the Internship, I had to work with two different teams. So for the first half of the Internship period, I worked with the Development team, where I worked on the Android platform. During the Later half of the period, I worked with the Computer Operations Team where I got to work on ARMS, software used by Air India for Ticket Management and Openrefine used for staff data and ticket data management.

## Education

Maharaja Agrasen Institute Of Technology
Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Information Technology (2014 - 2018)

Kendriya Vidyalaya Intermediate , Science stream · (2012 - 2013)

Kendriya Vidyalaya

High School · (2010 - 2011)